こんな… ダメなお兄ちゃんでも…
Championship Finals, round 7!
許してくれるか？ あい。
Ready...
キルア…
Killua wins!
好き。
Yes!
同じ失敗をするな。
Congratulations.
そして　謝るなら 俺にじゃなく　カイトにだ。
Here is your prize, the Sword of Truth.
どっちにしろ行け！ うん。
Sword of Truth
Sword that cuts through
anything false. Has been
used in trials to determine
criminals. Breaks if used
to cut something true,
but will regenerate if left
in scabbard for a day. This is card #83. It goes in a restricted slot.
仲間に謝る時は　ルールがある 知ってっか？
Okay, that's one down. Score!
ちょうど あんたみたいな赤毛だったよ。
Hmph, you're bluffing. I know that you just started this game.
俺が撃ち殺したのは。
Thief on! Attack Killua!
生かしたまま　とことん楽しむ ゲスだと知ってたからな。
Haven't you been training at all, Mister? Next time, I won't return your card.
アリに生まれ変わって
You must be an amateur.
「あぁ　同じこと繰り返してる」 って思ったよ。
I'm impressed you got into a game for Hunters.
俺は　こうなる前 人を消す仕事をしてた。
Th-That only works against weak players! Precisely.
それ以外の時間は 誰かを怒鳴ってればよかった。
If you want a card,
you take it from someone.
誰にでも　できる仕事さ。
Only fools would participate in tournaments.
生まれ変わっても 繰り返している ばかげたサイクル。
Understand, boys?
このコは　このサイクルから 逃がしてやりたいと思った。
Just forget it. Those guys were obviously pros. At least we didn't waste too much effort. Damn it!
難しい仕組みは　分からない。
Then I'm gonna start getting spell cards!
ただ　このまま　奴らに捕まって なぶられたあげく 死んじまったら
That means our next destination
will be Masadora, City of Magic. No objections!
そんなサイクルを…。
That's our base.
逃げてくれって 祈りながら撃った。
We'll begin assigning roles.
女王は何百って人間を食い その中で前世を持って 生まれ変わった者は　わずかだ。
You've probably heard that there
are forty different spell cards. We need you to obtain
one of those cards, Prison.
ほとんどの人間の魂は
This is one of the strongest defensive spells.
無事　どこかへ 逃げられたのかもしれない。
We could certainly use another one of these.
でも　俺はやりたかった。
In order to protect Breath of Archangel.
積極的に逃げる手助けをした気に なりたかった。
Breath of Archangel? A super-rare SS card that no one's
あんたが　あのコの代わりに そこに入ったってことは
ever been able to obtain.
あのコは　多分 逃げられたってことだろうし
How can you be certain no
one's gotten one before?
幸いなことに　俺は
There's a spell card called List.
「あんたに撃たれて死んだぜ」って 前世を持つアリには
When you cast it, you can learn the maximum
transformation limit of any card
まだ会ったことがない。
as well as the number of current card holders.
みんな　うまく 逃げてくれたんだろう。
I see.
こうなる前は 魂なんか信じちゃいなかった。
The card is very difficult to obtain because you must have all forty spell
cards before you can trade for one.
俺は基本的にノミやハエと 同価値の存在で　ただ生きて死ぬ。
But spell cards are extremely
useful in this game, so players tend to use them up.
自我なんてものは
However, we've been able
そいつらより少しばかり 脳が複雑になったための バグだと思っていた。
to collect all forty spell cards.
死んだら終わり 分解されて　ちりになる。
We would prefer to trade them in for
a Breath of Archangel at once... But then you'd have no cards to protect it.
そして　そこら中に散らばる。
That's why you need a copy of Prison.
俺は　そのちっぽけな 大量の粒には 意味がないと思ってた。
Exactly. At any rate, to carry out this plan, we'll need you all to memorize
the forty different spell cards.
全く別の姿なのに
They were pretty valuable.
俺として　同じようなばかを また繰り返してる。
We don't need to worry about money now. Let's buy some food and water,
so we can start for Masadora!
俺は考えた。
First, we'll need a map.
俺は　ばかだが
Map of Island
A detailed map
showing cities
and important
locations, as well
as useful information
such as hot spots!
今　分かってることを 否定しないし 分からないことを 素通りしたくない。
Map of Island
A blank map that
automatically fills in
locations as the owner
visits and gathers
information about them. The one with information costs 650,000, while the blank one is 20,000. Which one should we get?
俺は死んだ。
It'll be more fun to fill it in ourselves.
死んで分解され　小さく分かれた。
You're so positive, it's painful. Gain.
…と勝手に思ってた物質には
Head north for eighty kilometers.
俺の想像が及ばなかった 力があった。
After you pass the mountain,
you'll reach a lake. If you follow the lake north,
you should reach Masadora.
俺達の健康に影響を与えるほどの エネルギーを
Yep. Assuming you survive.
何万年　何億年と 出し続けることができる。 さらに小さなＤＮＡには
The mountain is crawling with bandits. And once you pass the mountain,
you'll encounter hordes of monsters. Bandits?
俺達のほとんどを形成する 膨大な量の情報が
Monsters? Now it sounds more like an RPG!
二重らせん状に詰まってる。
I wanna see these monsters! Let's hurry up!
さらに限りなく小さい 途方もなく小さいってことが
All right! Off we go! Please wait!
宇宙という莫大な空間を 生むための条件だったりする。 小さいという概念は
I beg you! What? Please let me join you!
そのものが発し得る エネルギーの総量と
Oh, sorry. Can't.
イコールではなかった。
Wh-Why not? You'd be a nuisance.
魂は　恐らく小さいが
Little brat...
繰り返すだけの エネルギーを持っていた。 それじゃ　俺は繰り返すために 生まれ変わったのか？
You dare call me a nuisance? If I chose to, I could mop the floor with
you, with one hand behind my back. That does it.
ここから先は分からない。 だから　全て　俺の感覚と 想像でしかないが
I was just going to tease these boys a little, but now I'm going to ruin their lives.
繰り返しちゃダメだと 俺の中のどこかが言って来る。
Hey, hold it right there! Please!
恐らく繰り返したり　やり直したり しなきゃいけないのは
I'll try really hard not to get in your way!
生きてるうちに 心に与えるべき何かが 足りなかったからだと思う。
Okay, I have most of the information we need. Then, can you tell us what you found?
肉体だって 心の踏ん切りがつかなきゃ 動きは鈍いだろ？
I tried a hundred different people in this city, and they all gave the same response
俺の場合　前も今もずっと
when faced with an unusual question.
このままでいいはずがないって 考えてる。
This is typical behavior
for in-game characters. Number two.
これが良くないんだと思う。
Book.
俺は　きっと　また繰り返す。 このままでいいはずがないと 思いながら…。
Rock
A normal rock found
on the ground.
Does decent damage
when thrown. This card is real. This one is a copy Kortopi made. Gain.
選択を間違ったからな。
Kortopi's card didn't transform.
俺が本当に撃つべきだったのは あのコじゃなく
I believe that means the game's program didn't recognize Kortopi's card.
追って来た連中だった。
Number three. Shizuku's vacuum works in this world, but it won't work on any items
with special abilities.
何てことはない 一番のゲスは俺だって話だ。
I think that's because the game was programmed
すすけた魂を 浄化するための代償が
so Nen couldn't be used to collect cards.
あまりに痛そうだったから
So? However, the above three points
それを避けたんだ。
indicate another possibility.
逃げてくれなんて 虫のいいことを祈りながら
This game isn't taking place
in a virtual world.
自分が傷つくまいと 必死だったんだ。
It's based somewhere in the real world. What do you mean?
俺は自分を守るため 彼女を撃った。 そして　姿だけ似てる あんたに　ざんげすることで
If the players actually entered the game, their spirits would detach from
their bodies and enter the console, leaving the bodies behind.
また自分だけ 救われようとしている。
Sending them physically into the
game would be unnecessary. And separating spirit from
body should require more
はぁ…　まったく…。
than standing before a console and using Hatsu.
救えない話さ。 最後まで聞いてくれて感謝する。
It's more logical that the players
are actually warped elsewhere.
待てよ　逃げるな。
Thus, Greed Island isn't a real game.
お前は　あたちと来い。
It's a trap that sends players who
use Hatsu here, to this island. That makes sense.
これから　ずっとだ。
But what does it mean?
お前が撃った　あたちのそばで
Do you remember the reward
for clearing this game?
これからずっと　これしかないって 生き方をするんだ。
Let's see... What was it? You can select three item cards
これは　お前の義務だ 選択の余地なんかない。 自ら死んでリセットなんて 誰が許すか。
from your restricted slots,
to take back to the real world. Right.
毎日　あたちに謝りながら生きろ。
That means these items can
be used outside the island.
二度と このままでいいのかなんて 暇で　くそな考えが もたげないくらい
If this game takes place in the real world, it should be possible to remove
こき使ってやる。
the treasure without clearing the game.
あたちに謝りながら あたちの言う通り働いて
I understand. Book.
あたちのために生きるんだ。
At the moment, we only
know about a few items.
もし　お前が
It would be ideal to learn all of the cards.
ちょっとでも 今の覚悟を忘れて堕落したら
So our first objective is
the spell card God Eye.
あたちが殺してやる。 安心して生きろ。
Now we just need to find Phinks and Feitan.
カイト　お客さんだよ。
But he was carrying a lot of spell cards.
通してくれ。
Well, let's split up for now. In one week, we'll meet in Masadora.
カイト？ ああ。
Hey, what should we do about her?
ごめん。
Just ignore her. Once the bandits show up,
we'll have a chance to ditch her.
来い　座れ。
Isn't that kind of mean? What are you talking about?
ん！ 何にだ？
I didn't think she'd keep up this long.
一緒に戦えなかった。
Let's take them. Yeah.
力が　足りなかった。
Please help us! We beg you! Huh?
あいつを…　ピトーを倒すのに
A disease is going around the island.
だいぶ　むちゃしたらしいな。 うん　死にかけた。
It starts with a mild fever, grows to a high fever, and
eventually leads to death.
それでも お前が俺の倒せなかった 敵を倒したのは事実だ。
All we can do is use medicine
to keep the fever in check.
俺の目に狂いはなかった …と負け惜しみを言っとくか。
But the medicine will only work for a week.
でも　キルアが… みんながいなかったら
It's also incredibly expensive, and we've run out of money...
俺は　ここにいなかった。 俺ひとりで　ここに 来られたわけじゃないんだ。
We've all fallen ill, so we're unable to do any bandit work.
お互い　修行が足りなかったな。
Is it contagious? That's just a scenario. My son only has two or three days to live!
あっ　ジンと話したの？ ああ。
Yeah, if we give them money, they should provide us with
items or information. Uh, how much do you need?
早く　戻ってやれ。
80,000 Jenny.
わざわざ来てくれて　うれしいよ。
So they know everything about us. Um, I have enough to cover 80,000 Jenny.
助けがいる時は 必ず　お前に連絡する。 キルアにも　よろしくな。
Ah, could you shut up for a moment? I'm gonna kill that brat.
俺達は　もう仲間だ。
We can give you 80,000 Jenny.
だから今は ジンさんのとこへ帰れ。
Really? Thank you so much! You've saved my son's life!
うん！
I'm c-cold. So cold...
悪かった。 何にだ？
That'd really be okay? You're like angels!
楽になりたくて 全てから逃げようとした。
Words are not enough... ...to express our gratitude!
苦しくても生きてみるよ。
Nah, we don't need thanks.
「精いっぱいやった」って 死ぬ時　思えるように。
How about some information or items?
ジン！
What was that about?
止めたんですけど。
We finally get to start fighting! Time to see what you've got.
確かに…　ここで待つとは 言ってなかったな…。
I wanna see what you accomplished
during your secret training.
さすが　世界最大の木。
Bingo! The eye is its weakness.
人類は人工の建造物で この木を超えることが いまだに　できておりません。 この木を登ることは 禁止されていませんが
They're moving around too much, but they're doing reasonably well.
登木料と契約書への サインが必要です。
Weaker than they looked. The card reverted after we
left it alone for a minute.
５００ｍ地点までは エレベーターか階段で行けますが
We can do this. The monsters come with weaknesses.
そこから先は命懸けです。
If we stay calm and think, we'll be fine.
年間　延べ約３０００人が 挑戦しますが
Okay. Let's head for Masadora, then.
９４％は１０００ｍまで達せず
Yeah!
年間　延べにして わずか３０名しかいないのです。
Huh?
じゃあ。
That didn't hurt. This one's weak.
俺達は　ここで。 うん。
But it's fast! Let's catch it.
うん。
Damn!
キルア　いろいろホントに ありがとう！ おう。
Watch the trajectory,
not its current location.
まぁ　目の前で 「俺ひとりで倒すから」って はぶられたり
With observation, you can learn an
opponent's pattern of motion.
「お前　関係ねえから」って 言われた時は
Your eyes are sharp, but you
aren't using them properly.
相当　落ちたけどな。
It got away from us.
うぅ…　ホントに　ごめんよ。
Well, it won't take very
long to reach Masadora if they're all this weak.
お兄ちゃん！ ムフっ。
Don't be stupid!
まぁ　もう謝ってもらったし お前と旅したおかげで
What if you encounter a monster
that's both strong and fast?
あっ　ちなみに　お前のこと 治したの　こいつだから。 えっ？　それホント？
Bubbles?
何で　こんなタイミングで？
It's gone...
もっと早く言ってくれれば よかったのに！ もう！ 悪ぃ…。
It's loud and generates a shock wave, but it doesn't do any damage.
知ってる奴がいっぱいいると ちょっとな…。
When you touch them, the red ones don't pop.
まぁ 複雑な家庭の事情があってよ。
The white bubbles pop
ちょっと　こっち！
when they make contact with a human aura.
アルカ　ナニカ呼んでいいか？ うん。
The red ones pop when they make
contact with anything else.
お。
To catch that horse, you must
identify which bubble is which, then switch between Zetsu and Ten.
こいつの能力は　俺のお願いを 何でも　かなえてくれる っていうものなんだけど。
That's still too difficult for them.
何でも？ そのすご過ぎる能力のせいで
Still...
家に閉じ込められっ放し だったんだ。
These boys are...
こいつは　お前がきっかけで こうして外に出られたし
These boys are just wasting their potential!
俺も　こいつを 一生かけて守る覚悟ができた。
They're raw stones that'll shine like
diamonds with a little polishing!
ホントは　感謝してんのは 俺達のほうなんだよ。
But at this rate, they'll run into
stronger players or monsters, and it'll be game over!
そ…　そんな。 俺のほうこそ　本当にありがとう！
This one looks tougher. That's it...
ダメだ　これ以上いたら…。 だな。
See that? The armor's just a puppet, so attacks won't work against it.
俺は　これから　アルカと いろんなとこ旅するから
Here it is!
何かあったら　すぐ連絡してよ！ 俺もそうするから。
I got the card!
ああ　頼りにしてるぜ。
So you can use Gyo.
いっぱい　貸してるからな。 ぐっ…。
Why didn't you use it before?
親父さんによろしくな。 うん！
Uh, well... Yeah...
本当は一緒に行きたいけど アルカいるし。
So you forgot.
まだ　水入らずで 話してねえんだろ？ また今度な。
Why are you just standing there? Gyo!
お兄ちゃん　解放しますから。
What do you see? The number 1.
また遊んであげてくださいね。
Good. Listen up.
ちょい待て！ あげてんのは俺のほう！
If I lift my finger, you use Gyo.
いい妹だろ？ 悪ぃけど　お前　二の次だから。
And then you holler out what you see.
アハハハ…　ハハハ…。
If you ever sense anything suspicious, use Gyo. Got it?
ん！
Wait, why are you ordering us around?
The number 5!
カイトも言ってたよ！
Who do you think you are?
俺達　どこにいても
Oh, I haven't introduced myself yet.
仲間だから！
I'm the pro Hunter Biscuit Krueger.
おう！
I first learned Nen forty years ago.
じゃあ… また！
God Eye
Grants the user the effects
of Analysis and List on
cards 001-099 at any time.
(Effect lasts until player
leaves the game.)
[LR][CONT] If you use this spell, you get
a description of a given card, number of holders, and total
number of cards in existence. I want one! Continue!